<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C on Vineel Kovvuri</title>
    <link>/tags/c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C on Vineel Kovvuri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 18:33:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Newbie&#39;s Introduction To Compilation Process And Reverse Engineering</title>
      <link>/blog/a-newbies-introduction-to-compilation-process-and-reverse-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 18:33:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/a-newbies-introduction-to-compilation-process-and-reverse-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Compilers are surely the complex programs of all times. Even today, writing a compiler with minimum set of tools is considered to be challenging. This tutorial scratches the surface of different compiler phases involved in translating a given source code to executable and also shows how this information is useful in context of reverse engineering.&#xA;GNU compiler collection provides an excellent set of tools for dissecting the compilation process and to understand the working of bits and bytes in the final executable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Libspng - C Language Case Study</title>
      <link>/blog/c-case-studies/f/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 18:33:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/c-case-studies/f/</guid>
      <description>Build System It uses meson build system to build the library&#xA;Data Structures It is not using any fancy data structures instead it relies on plain array of objects and uses the traditional realloc function to expand them.&#xA;Miscellaneous All variables are declared as when needed. This deviates from Linux source code. In Linux kernel, declarations are done only in the beginning of a new scope (either at the start of the function or start of a scope)</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
